Good morning, Jaylen. How you doing this
morning?
>> Doing good, Jeff. How are you?
>> Good. Good. Thanks for Thanks for
joining us. Um Dan Morgan signed three
of the top, arguably the top 10 free
agents uh on the market, and that's
something that was unthinkable a few
years ago. Um in your case, why did you
join the Panthers? And is a perception
of playing for the Panthers changed
among the NFL players?
Yeah, I think that what the team was
able to accomplish last year was
extremely impressive and I think
everybody kind of recognized the
organization as a contender and you know
somebody a team that's up and coming. Um
so you know it's I think Dan did an
awesome job of you know who he signed.
Um and I'm just excited to come in and
contribute to what the team was already
doing in the you know upwards trajectory
of of what the organization was doing.
Just one quick followup. Uh um as a new
leader of the room, how important is it
to you to mentor Scorton and Princely
and to create something that hasn't
that's been missing for a long time, a
consistent pass rush?
>> Yeah, you know, I think I think you
know, them two in particular, super
talented young guys. You know, I saw
them jumping out on film a lot last year
when I was doing film study. So, you
know, I'm just excited to come in. You
know, obviously I'm not like a 10 15
year vet, but I've, you know, played in
this league a fair amount and I have
some good experience. So, you know, I
think that I can come in and, you know,
help contribute from whether it's a
mental standpoint or just, you know,
whatever guidance they need. Uh, and I'm
sure they're going to, you know, help me
out with a lot of things, too. So, I'm
excuse me, I'm excited to get in that
room and just start building that bond
with the guys.
>> Hey, thanks. Good luck in Carolina.
>> Thanks, Jeff.
>> Hey, Jaylen. David Newton with ESPN.com.
Congratulations.
wanted to ask you uh kind of your
emotions when you got the the big deal
with Carolina compared to what you were
feeling way back when the injuries
forced you to basically give up football
or thought you were giving up football.
>> Yeah. You know, if you had told me that
this uh this was going to happen a
handful of years ago, uh you know, I
might have told you you're crazy. Um you
know, I always had the belief in myself.
I've always known, you know, what I can
accomplish, but, you know, truthfully
with this game, you never know. Um, you
know, especially backto-back injuries,
it was it was definitely, you know, a
tough time that I had to go through and
I just put my head down and, you know,
continue to have faith in the process,
have faith in God and that, you know, if
I just, you know, kept doing my job and
that everything was going to work itself
out. But, uh, it was a pretty surreal
moment when it happened and, uh, you
know, I really wouldn't rather be
anywhere else but the Panthers. So, it's
just I'm just very grateful for for
everything. Now, what did your parents
mean back then and and their musical
background is amazing. So, how how did
their influence and knowing the music
side that you actually got into? Um, how
how did that all play into everything?
>> Yeah. So, I mean, music kind of found
me. Like I said, I grew up in a a
musical family. Grandfather's a symphony
conductor. Both parents were
instrumentalists. You know, I grew up
playing the piano some. But, uh, when I
retired from UCLA, that's when I really
poured myself into into music. And you
know, it was there for me in a time when
I needed it the most. It was very
cathartic for me. Uh it allowed me to
start to establish an identity outside
of the sport, which you know, as as you
guys all uh know very well, it's it's
very hard for guys sometimes when they
stop, you know, when they stop playing
their sport, trying to find their
identity, trying to figure out what
they're going to do with their life. So,
you know, I was able to have that
opportunity. And then when I got back
into the sport, it just gave me a whole
different appreciation of uh you know,
what the sport means to me. And you
know, ever since then, just I've been
able to focus on on football obviously,
but still have music as something
that's, you know, I'm passionate about
in the offseason or just whether it's as
a listener, as a producer, engineer, um
something that still plays a pivotal
part in my life. And uh you know, in
terms of my parents, you know, just
being there to support me through
everything, obviously, you know, they
encouraged me when it came to the music,
but you know, my dad in particular just
always told me, he's like, "Man, I
really think that you can get back into
football and still do something special
with it." And at first I didn't believe
him, but uh you know we we buted heads,
we went back and forth, but ultimately
you know kind of took his guidance on
that and and uh I know it was a very
special moment for both him and I uh
when I did sign this contract and we're
able to just kind of look back and
reminisce on you know 2018 when when
like I said I was just arguing with him
every day. I don't want to do it. It's
not for me. Um so it's it's a blessing
man and I just I'm so thankful for them
for supporting me and you know for you
know everything that's that's gotten to
this moment.
Appreciate it. Thank you very much.
>> Let's do it.
>> Scott Fowler followed by Mike K.
>> Hi Jaylen. Um, I wanted to ask you for
people who have not seen you play
regularly. How would you describe
yourself as a player?
>> Oh man, max effort, tenacious,
disruptive. I think that's that's three
kind of words I can describe it briefly.
Um, you know, I think that I still have
room to grow obviously as a as a pass
rusher and uh, you know, I I kind of
used this this phrase uh, when I was
talking to the team, you know, a couple
days ago, but just turning all that
disruption into production. You know, I
think that's kind of the next step of my
career, but uh, at the at the bare
minimum, I'm a disruptive force. Uh, you
know, I go out there with max effort
with with huge heart. Um, I'm a team guy
and you know, I just try to bring my
teammates along with me. Um, but you
know, when I get on that field, man,
it's it's instinctive. It's fast. Uh,
and it's it's like I said, it's balls to
the wall 100% every time.
>> One other thing, uh, with that great big
contract, do you have any plans for that
money or have you ever made a splurge
purchase on it yet?
>> I'm buying a house, man. I'm I'm buy a
nice house in in Charlotte. Um, nice
backyard with a pool and uh, you know, a
place for for my, you know, future wife,
fiance currently and baby boy that's
coming in a couple days to feel settled
and, you know, build our family. Um, but
I'm a car guy, too. So, I'll probably
get another classic Porsche and, uh, you
know, get give my wife something nice.
Um, but, you know, I also, um, just, you
know, using that money to support my
family, to, uh, support my loved ones,
um, and to, yeah, make a difference. I'm
sure eventually I'll make some more
sports purchases. I like watches, too.
So, if you see if you see me rocking a
new AP, don't ask questions.
You know where that came from. But yeah,
man. I'm just I'm excited to to be able
to have this freedom and uh you know,
it's a blessing.
>> Congratulations.
>> Thank you.
>> Hi, Jaylen. Congratulations.
This year, guys were able to have Zoom
calls with I mean, obviously, this is
your first 4A into free agency, but guys
were able to have Zoom calls. Were you
able to take part in a Zoom call before
you agreed to terms? And if so, what did
you learn about the organization from
that Zoom call if you did?
>> Yeah, I honestly didn't even have a Zoom
call. It was it all happened very
quickly. It was it was within the span
of, you know, basically, you know, found
out that the Panthers were interested on
like a Friday and then, uh, you know, my
agent kind of dealt with everything. I
trusted him and deferred to him to, you
know, um, negotiate well and do all
that. And then, you know, when the offer
came in, then I was able to, you know,
talk to the coaches, talk to Dan, do all
that. And uh it was it was a match made
in heaven. Honestly, it's I think that
we're all very like-minded and you know
I know what their goals are and they
know what my goals are. So uh like I do
think that it was a really good fit for
me and like I said I wouldn't rather be
anywhere else. I'm very grateful to the
Panthers organization and you know
everybody involved in bringing me out
here.
>> With that fit in that match, there's
obviously a lot of carryover from Vic
Fangio's defense to this one. Um DJ
obviously having a background with him
and and adapting some of his
philosophies. Why do you think you were
so successful specifically in Vic's
defense?
>> Um you know I think that the way that
Vic utilizes uh really the whole defense
but you know especially the edge players
the defensive front uh you know I think
it just allows me to play free. It's
it's um it's not easy but it's simple.
uh you know there's not a ton of
different um moving pieces when it comes
to you know pre-play adjustments things
like that. It's pretty much you know a
lot of the whether he's running nickel
especially you know lineup rush that's
it and so for me that just allows me to
clear my head and to you know trust my
reads use my eyes and my instincts to to
play and you know when I am asked to
drop in coverage when I am asked to you
know do different things within the you
know 34 scheme uh you know I can do
those things as well. So, uh, but at the
core of it, I just think that it's it's,
um, you know, very conducive to
instinctive and quick and and kind of
mindless, you could say, play.
>> Joe Pson, followed by Gabe McDonald.
>> Hey Jaylen, thanks for doing this. I'm
uh, with the Athletic here in town. U,
you referenced this a minute ago, but
the turning that disruption into
production. How do you do that? what
what's what's because obviously your
your pressure rates have been, you know,
among some of the highest in the league.
>> Yeah, you know, I think that some of
that is is out of my control. You know,
you can, you know, make a crazy
disruptive play and the quarterback
rolls out to the other side or somebody
else makes a sack or he gets the ball
off, you know, especially in the league
nowadays. Like I think the quarterbacks
are really good at at being efficient
and getting the ball off quickly. But,
you know, there are a lot of situations
where, you know, I do beat my guy and
I'm at the top of the rush and whether
it's, you know, that extra bend or it's
that's, you know, being on point with my
hands, whether it's finishing the rush,
like there's just, you know, football is
truly a game of inches. Uh, and so I
think that for me to just keep honing in
on the technique and fundamentals, um,
and getting to that that that point, you
know, I've I've always had confidence
and I've never had a problem with
getting to that point. It's just a
matter of finishing sometimes. So, you
know, I think knowing uh you know, what
I need to work on, you know, getting
with my coaches and uh and really honing
that in, that's going to make a big
difference. And then there were uh you
obviously agreed to terms within the
first hour of the the legal tampering
period, but there were reports that the
night before that the Eagles were going
to make a very aggressive push. Did that
happen? And and how close were the were,
you know, the the negotiations between
those two teams and maybe even any
others? Yeah, I mean out of respect for
them, you know, I don't want to disclose
what they were offering or anything like
that, but um you know, they definitely
did want me to come back. Um and you
know, that's something I knew after the
season that they were going to be making
a push and um but ultimately, you know,
Panthers just um they they came with
more attractive offer and you know,
clearly that just shows the belief they
have in me, the belief they have in
their team. They're willing to invest
in, you know, pieces to try to take this
team to the next the next um the next
level. So, uh, yeah, you know, it's it
was it came down to it, but ultimately
it was it was kind of a no-brainer to to
come to the Panthers.
>> Gabe,
>> hey, what's up? Uh, Jaylen Gay McDonald
from the local Fox affiliate here in
town. Uh, recently saw the uh, miked up
video after you guys played when you
were in Miami coming here in Carolina.
Said you had a lot of homies on the
team. just those relationships, how did
how are those going to help in the
transition when you think about a lot of
former teammates from your days with
previous teams, especially a guy like
Rob Hunt, you know, just helping in the
transition getting here?
>> Yeah, I mean, it's really cool to be
able to go somewhere new. Uh, you know,
I kind of compare going to a new team,
it's like going to a new school when
you're young. Uh, and frankly, in that
situation, like you really don't know
anybody typically. So, uh, for me to
come into a new team and already be
familiar with some of the guys, I think
that, you know, it'll help a little bit
of the transition, but ultimately I'm
just going to come in and be myself.
And, uh, you know, I know that the guys,
uh, are going to be great, and I'll be
able to make relationships pretty
quickly. And I'm just excited to really
get in the building and get to know
everybody.
>> Alex Zitlo, followed by Desan.
>> Hey Jaylen, thanks again for taking the
time to do this. Um, I wanted to ask
about being uh, traded in the middle of
the year last year. What was that
experience like having to um, be in one
system one week and then another system
the next?
>> Yeah, I mean it was pretty hectic. Um,
it all happened super fast kind of like
this free agency did. But, um, you know,
it was like I just said before, it was
kind of like going to a new school, you
know, new team. You know, luckily I
obviously playing under Vic before like
there was a little bit of familiarity
when it came to the scheme and
everything like that. But uh you know, I
just came in and uh you know, kudos to
everybody in that organization. They
really, you know, embraced me when I
came in and helped me with my
transition. Um but you know, also when
it comes to me, like I've always been a
guy who, you know, I want to earn my
teammates and my coaches respect first
and foremost. So, you know, I don't come
in with with any sort of arrogance or,
you know, any sort of um
standoffishness, if that's a word, but
uh it is
But uh you know just you coming in being
humble and and you know really like I
said I have a lot of respect for you
know what what the guys on the
organization do and you know what
they've been able to establish there
already. So for me it's not about trying
to come in and step on any toes or you
know assert dominance or anything like
that. It's just like coming in as a
humble worker and uh you know learning
the system, learning the guys and and uh
putting my best foot forward. So that's
really what I'm going to do you know
coming into the Panthers organization.
come in, you know, gain the respect of
my coaches, my teammates, um, you know,
the city, everything like that, and
just, you know, give my best effort
every day.
>> Um, and a quick followup to that, you
you've been in the NFL for 5 years. Uh,
you're well established, obviously, but
I'm still curious, is there like, I
don't know, any misconception about your
game that you want to prove wrong coming
to Carolina or anything like that?
I mean, I guess really the only knock
you can or knock you can say about me is
that I don't have a bunch of sacks,
which uh you know, as we all know is
kind of um
it's not that it's irrelevant.
Obviously, production matters. Um but at
the end of the day, like you know, as
long as you're being disruptive, as long
as you're making an impact, making
plays, you know, this game is about a
lot more than sacks. So, uh you know, I
do want to get those sack numbers up. I
I've always known that I can be a 10
plus 13 plus guy and you know to be able
to come and and and really for my own
personal uh goals and and you know what
I want to accomplish in this league too
like I want to you know establish myself
as you know one of the top top elite
guys uh and I think parts of our game
are elite um but I think that just
making everything you know bringing it
all into one um you know I think that's
kind of a misconception you can say um
but you know everybody who knows knows
you know if if you watch me play if you
see the stats if you see the the ingame
production or disruption, you know, you
know that that uh you know, I try to I
try to do a good job, man, and I do make
an impact on the field. So, I'm just
going to continue to to keep trying to
do that and and uh you know, elevate my
game in every way.
>> Awesome, man. Thanks,
>> Jaylen. Good morning. I was curious, it
sounds like you have a lot of life
milestones happening all at once in
addition to the new contract, a fiance,
a father to be. What has that part of
the process been like? you starting all
these new chapters at once.
>> Oh man, it's uh this this month of March
was uh I was looking forward to it for a
while just knowing that everything was
coming. I didn't know where I was going
to be, but I knew I was going to be
signing somewhere. Um you know,
obviously uh our due dates been end of
March this whole time. My sister got
married this past weekend. So, uh it's
it's been a truly special time. And you
know, leading up to it, it was one of
those things where I kind of felt myself
super antsy and impatient and just
wanted everything to come. Um, but then
it just came all in once. And so at this
point, I'm really just trying to soak
everything in and be present. Uh, you
know, especially with the little one
coming, you know, you can't get that
time back. So for me, just taking it day
by day, uh, appreciating every day,
appreciating the the monotonous times,
appreciating the hard times, the good
times. Uh, and then when I do come,
because obviously I'm looking forward to
starting OCAs and moving to Charlotte
and doing all that. Um, but it's going
to come when it comes and I can't make
time go any faster. So, uh, for the time
being, I'm just going to, like I said,
be present and be grateful for every
day.
>> Awesome. Congratulations and on the
wedding for your sister.
>> Thank you. It was awesome.
>> We're going to end with David Newton,
followed by Mike K.
>> Hey, I appreciate another question here.
Um, you just had a sack on Bryce Young
this past season. Um, have you followed
his career very much and just kind of
how how do you have you seen him evolve
as a quarterback?
>> Yeah, I mean obviously him being a SoCal
guy, I've been in tune with what he has
going on over the last couple years and,
you know, all I can say about him is I
have a lot of respect for, you know, the
way he's dealt with adversity. Uh, you
know, obviously I know his his career so
far hasn't been, you know, this perfect,
you know, linear straight path or
whatever, but, you know, ultimately it
never really is. And um I think it's
it's more of a testament to him and it's
more impressive to him that he's been
able to go through starting, getting
benched, coming back and for him to to
always be a team guy to continue to
believe in himself to continue to work
hard and to come in last year and you
know really kind of uh boost the
organization and and uh take them to you
know the playoff appearance and you know
really almost a playoff win. Um, so you
know, I know that that I don't know him
ultra well personally, but you I'm
excited to get to know him and I'm
excited to see how he continues to grow
as a leader on this team.
>> Sorry about the dog barking there, but I
want to ask you too, um, you've been on
some good defenses. So, how close is
this defense of what you've seen from,
you know, just looking at it quickly,
what you've added with you and Lloyd,
how close this defense to being up in
that elite level you think it you want
it to be?
Yeah, I think that's that that's up to
us. You know, I think that we have the
pieces and we have the talent and you
know, we're going to go as far as as
we're able to take this thing. So, um
you know, it's we can't just sit here
and say, "Oh, yeah, we have all this
talent." We're automatically going to be
incredible. Like, it takes hard work. It
takes, you know, all this time that
we're going to be spending the
offseason, you know, building this and
cultivating what we have. Uh, you know,
I think the potential is is out of the
roof, but I think ultimately it comes
down to, you know, who we want to be and
and how we attack it on a daily on a
daily basis.
>> Thanks again.
>> Hey Jaylen, talking to folks that worked
with you in Philly, they said when you
got there, it was like you had been
there forever. You were really quick to
adapt, really quick to make friends.
Dave Canalis and Dan Morgan are huge on
culture. Um, I'm I'm just curious,
what's your approach to entering a new
locker room? And then also off the field
getting involved in the community with
your foundation.
>> Yeah, I mean I think my approach is just
humility and hard work. You know, I
think that's everything it comes down
to. Like ultimately, um, you know, like
I said, I'm not trying to come in and
step on any toes, but you know, knowing
that, you know, the investment they put
into me, the expectations they have for
me to, you know, to be a leader on this
team, to be a driving force in in the
direction this team is trying to go in,
uh, you know, I'm going to come in, I'm
going to work hard, uh, I'm going to be
myself. And so ultimately I believe that
you know they'll appreciate that and
they'll you know I'm going to get along
with who I get along with and you know
I'm an easygoing guy so you know for me
I'm just excited to to come in and start
building those relationships. And then
when it comes to the the community like
I'm extremely excited I've heard amazing
things about um you know Carolina about
Charlotte. Uh and so for me with my you
know foundation um you know in in the
music space and coming in and you know
giving uh giving kids and and
underserved communities you know the
opportunity to learn about music um
music production, music business, all
these different facets of music. Uh it's
really exciting. You know I know my
mom's excited for it. She basically runs
my foundation. uh and we've been kind of
waiting for me to be settled so that we
can really go full force ahead with this
and you know so I think that it's going
to be really cool to be able to get in
the community and just uh you know do as
much as I can to to make an impact and
to change